Guide to the New York State College of Human Ecology Ghana Project records, 1961-1988.
New York State College of Human Ecology Ghana Project records, 1961-1988.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
New York State College of Human Ecology Ghana Project records, 1961-1988.
23-2-2703
New York State College of Human Ecology. Ghana Project.
1 c.f.
Reports, correspondence, lists, syllabi, plans, clippings, photographs, and other materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Ghana Project records, including description of the project, reports, correspondence, lists, syllabi, plans, clippings, and photographs and the work done by Professor Kathleen Rhodes.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Ghana Project records, including description of the project, reports, correspondence, lists, syllabi, plans, clippings, and photographs and the work done by Professor Kathleen Rhodes.
SUBJECTS
Names:
New York State College of Human Ecology. Ghana Project.; Rhodes, Kathleen.
Subjects:
International cooperation.; Home economics--International cooperation.; African cooperation.
Places:
Africa--American influences.; Ghana--Study and teaching.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
SERIES LIST
Series I. Photographs
A. Reception Photos
B. Picnic and Barbecue Photos
C. Ithaca Sr. High Photos
D. Extension Classes and Workshop Photos
E. Miscellaneous Photos
Series II. Slides
Series III. Documents
Series IV. Memorabilia
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Photographs
  - A. Reception Photos
    - Dr. Hazel Hauck, Efunjoke Coker, Olusola S. Banjo, Pricilla Adewale, Margaret Kitchener Olowu., 1 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Margaret Kitchener Olowu, Edgar Clemens, Pat Husar, Ethel Mapoma, Olusola S. Banjo, 2 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Reception with Home Economics students, 3 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Carol Waslien, Prof. Esther Stocks, Prof. Catherine Personius, Dr. Verna Carely, Efunjoke Coker, 4 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Dr. Hazel Hauck, Lati Hyde-Forster, Lottie E. A. Hamilton-Hazeley, 5 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Margaret Olowu, Prof. Helen Cady, 6 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Lillian Hill, Samira Seif, 7 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Ezerina Mwaipopo, 8 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Ethel Mapoma, Hazel Hauck, Dean Helen G. Canoyer, 9 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Lottie E. A. Hamilton, Hazeley, Jane Levin, Joan Ryan, Margaret FitzGerald, Mary Rice, Diane Handy, Prof. Nancy Hoddick, 10 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Flossie H. Chokani, 11 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Dr. Verna A. Carley, Samira Seif, 12 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Victoria Mutswairo, Sister St. Jeanne Laval, 13 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Dorice A. C. Martinson, 14 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - B. Picnic and Barbecue Photos
    - Alberta Addo, Dorice A. C. Martinson, 1 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Efunjoke Coker, 2 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Ezerina Mwaipopo, Lottie E. A. Hamilton-Hazeley, Lati Hyde-Forster, 3 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Margaret Kitchener Olowu, Prof. Emeritus Lucille Williamson, 4 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Alberta Addo, Ethel Mapoma, Flossie H. Chokani, Ezerina Mwaipopo, Dean Helen G. Canoyer, 5 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Olusola S. Banjo, 6 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - C. Ithaca Sr. High Photos
    - Alberta Addo, Pricilla Adewale, Saada Barwani, Victoria Mutswairo, Mary Wood, Marcia Robinson, 1 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Alberta Addo, Pricilla Adewale, Saada Barwani, Victoria Mutswairo, Mary Wood, Marcia Robinson, 2 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Margaret Kitchener Olowu, Pamela Ogot, Olusola S. Banjo, Ethel Mapoma, 3 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Efunjoke Coker, Pamela Ogot, Ethel Mapoma, Olusola S. Banjo, Mary Wood, 4 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Olusola S. Banjo, Ezerina Mwaipopo, Pricilla Adewale, Pamela Ogot, 5 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - D. Extension Classes and Workshops Photos
    - Ethel Mapoma, Prof. Dorothy Proud, Saada Barwani, Lati Hyde-Forster, Ezerina Mwaipopo, 1 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Dorice A. C. Marginson, Saada Barwani, Lottie E. A. Hamilton-Hazeley, Samira Seif, 2 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Dorice Martinson, Marjorie Burns, Ruthe Thomas, 3 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Anne Row, Margaret Kitchener Olowu, 4 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Frances Grauman, Dorothy Johnson, Victoria Mutswairo, 5 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Hazel Reed, Samira Seif, 6 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Rita Raymond, Gulzar Sunderji, Margaret Kitchener Olowu, 7 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Efunjoke Coker, Marion Graves, 8 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Prof. Vera Caulum, Flossie H. Chokani, Samira Seif, Dr. Verna A. Carley, Ethel Mapoma, Prof. Dorothy Proud, Saada Berwani Lati Hyde-Forster, Victoria Mutswairo, 9 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Frances Grauman, Victoria Mutswairo, 10 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Ethel Mapoma, Pricilla Adewale, 11 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Pauline Wade, Lottie Hamilton-Hazeley, 12 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Ezerina Mwaipopo, Prof. Madeline Blum, Ethel Mapoma, 13 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Pamela Ogot, Ethel Mapoma, 14 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - E. Miscellaneous Photos
    - Olusola S. Banjo, Foreign Student, 1 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Latin Hyde-Forster, Olusola S. Banjo, Pricilla Adewale, Margaret Kitchener olowu, Pamela Ogot, Alberta Addo, Gulzar Sunderji, Ezerina Mwaipopo, Lottie E. A. Hamilton Hazeley, Efunjoke Coker, Saada Barwani, 2 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Lati Hyde-Forster, Lottie E. A. Hamilton-Hazeley, 3 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Gulzar Sunderji, Samira Seif, Pricilla Adewale, Pamela Ogot, Olusola S. Banjo, Ethel Mapoma, Ezerina Mwaipopo, Flossie H. Chokani, 4 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Pamela Ogot, David Twardock, Martha Raimon, Eva Raimon, Miriam Taitz, 5 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Efunjoke Coker, 6 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Pricilla Adewale, Saada Berwani, Pamela Ogot, Alberta Addo, Gulzar Sunderji, Lottie E. A. Hamilton-Hazeley, 7 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - David Bechoffer, David Twardock, Pamela Ogot, Martha Raimon, Rebecca Holmes, Prof. Clara Melville, Deborah Thomas, Ethel Mapoma, 8 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - David Bechoffer, David Twardock, Pamela Ogot, Martha Raimon, Rebecca Holmes, Prof. Clara Melville, Deborah Thomas, Ethel Mapoma, Gilbert Crawford, 9 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Gulzar Sunderji, Pamela Ogot, Margaret Kitchener Olowu, 10 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Gulzar Sunderji, 11 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Saada Berwani, Mrs. Gerega, Mrs. Asyro, Ezerina Mwaipopo, Emma Yonjo, Gulzar Sunderji, Samira Seif, 1 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Gulzar Sunderji, Olusola S. Banjo, Samira Seif, Lottie E. A. Hamilton-Hazeley, 2 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Alberta Addo, 3 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Mrs. Gerega, Emma Yonjo, 4 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Lati Hyde-Forster, Lottie E. A. Hamilton-Hazeley, 5 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Joan Holland, Freda Guilliam, Frankie MacHugh, 6 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Unknown, 7 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Nigeria, 8 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Dorice Martinson, 9 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Victoria Mutswairo, 10 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Sarah Caldwell, Camilla Low, Verna Carley, Willa Player, Helen Hifferman, Helen Canoyer, 11 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Photographs from Ghana 1963-64 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Photographs of Visit of African Educators to College of Home Economics 1961 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- Series II. Slides
  - Kenya Slides (Box 2, Folder 7-9)
  - Nigeria Slides (Box 2, Folder 10-12)
  - Miscellaneous Slides (Box 2, Folder 13-14)
- Series III. Documents
  - Description of Project; Progress Reports (1, 2, 3); "The International Heritage of Home Economics in USA" by Kathleen Rhodes, AHEA-Ghana., 1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Report of 1961 Visit of African Educators to the NYS College of Home Economics at Cornell University; Report on visit to Ghana by Kathleen Rhodes, Project Statement, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Survey Conducted by Students at Winneba College and student autobiographies; April 1963 Report on 2nd Visit to Ghana by Kathleen Rhodes, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence regarding Agreement with Ghana Steering committee minutes., May 1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Project Statement (revised); Oct., Nov., Dec. correspondence., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence and reports from Ghana, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Plans for and reports of consultant conference in Ghana; Reports from consultants, needs of Home Science program and proposed budget; Arrangements for visitors from Ghana. Report from Wood on Ghana situation. Correspondence regarding Home Demonstration Agents participation., 1964 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Proposed phases of Cornell-Ghana project; Correspondence regarding Rhodes visits to Ghana; Report by Flemming (University of Ghana); Arrangements for visit by Jiagge (Ghana); Report regarding Cornell-Ghana project Wilson., 1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Advisory Committee minutes; Regulations for Diploma in Home Science; Needs of Home Science Program (Rhodes); statement of project; Reports (Newkirk and Feldman), 1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Letters from Newkirk; clippings from Ghana Times; Advisory Committee minutes, personnel recruitment for '65-'66., 1964 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Summary report Sept.-Jan. (Newkirk); Letters to and from Newkirk regarding salary funding., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Letters from Narrowsburg Home Demonstration unit; Colson (U of Ghana) to Wilson (U of Ghana); Flemming (U of Ghana) to Colson., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Advisory Committee Minutes (3/3/65); Letters Canoyer (CU) to Brown (Ghana); Wood to Newkirk; Wilson to Canoyer; Wood to Flemming; Canoyer to Doulo (Ghana); Newkirk to Wood; Wood to Armbruster; O'Brien (U of Ghana) to Wood, Newkirk to Damatey (Ghana); Feldman and Newkirk to Wood; Canoyer to O'Brien., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Institutions Cooperating with CU-Ghana program. Advisory Committee minutes; letters Canoyer to Miller (Ghana); Canoyer to Pres. Perkins; Newkirk to Wood; Project report Feb.-March (Newkirk, memoranda on future projects, review of commitments), 1965 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Advisory Comm. memo; report to college faculty and minutes; correspondence need for Home Science degree; recommendations regarding Home Science (U of Ghana)., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Letters Wood and Newkirk; Communications regarding project development., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Reports of social science consultant; memo of understanding (CU and U of Ghana); Letters Muller (CU) to Canoyer; Wood to Edzii (U of Ghana) and Newkirk; Newkirk to Wood; Advisory Committee minutes., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Letters, Canoyer to Middlemast (H Dagent); Muller to Wood; Wood to Olds; Ambassador Williams; Newkirk; Kwapong (U of Ghana); Anderegg; Review of memo of understanding and budget., 1965 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Memos to Advisory Committee regarding plans for HSC building at U of Ghana; award of Fulbright to V. Cukler for 66-67; letter Canoyer to Addo (Ghana), 1966 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Report (Newkirk); letter Newkirk regarding building plans; Advisory Committee minutes; Revised draft of Memo of Understanding., 1966 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Comments on Ghana contract and memo of understanding; Final report on Cornell-Ghana project., 1966 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Letter Wood to Cutter; memos from Cutter; draft of proposed site visit to U of Ghana by USAID., 1966 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Advisory Committee memo regarding planning HSC facilities at U of Ghana; description of program for FAO; letters between Wood and Cutter; Statements; "Education of Women in Ghana"; "Women's Education and Development of Community Health.", 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Winneba College syllabi; Nutrition; Applied Chemistry and Physics; Regulations for 1963; Plan for '65 grads., 1963 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Winneba College Regulations; statement of project., 1964 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Winneba College syllabi for Foods and Nutrition; Social Science; Regulations for Home Science Diploma, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Materials on clothing and textiles for home science diploma. (Box 1, Folder 27-28)
  - Research Studies; Home Science course 1964-1965, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Requests for financial assistance, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Newspaper clippings: Ghana, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 31-32)
  - Newspaper clippings: Ghana, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 33-34)
  - Newspaper clippings: Ghana, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 35-36)
  - Lati Hyde-Forster's Closing Speech in a letter from Helen G. Canoyer, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Series IV. Memorabilia
  - Two silver trays and a pin - MU#1133 (Box 3)